Here's a problem you may have experienced in the past.
你以前可能遇到过 这种问题
Using an app on your phone, you tap a button.
使用手机上的一个应用时 点击一个按钮
That button is intended to do a bunch of work.
该按钮将执行 一系列操作
Let's say it's going to grab data from the Internet, play some music, or
例如 它会从 Internet 中 获取数据、播放音乐或
do some heavy number crunching to apply a blur effect on some image.
进行一些数据处理从而在 图片上应用模糊效果
Once that button is clicked, though, your program appears frozen for
但是点击这个按钮之后 你的程序会出现
what feels like an uncomfortable amount of time.
短时间的停滞 而这段时间 让人感觉很不舒服
This is super janky.
这非常令人讨厌
You're not sure if the thing has crashed or what.
你不确定程序是崩溃了 还是出现了其他问题
The, after a few moments,
但是片刻之后
suddenly everything comes back under your control.
一切又突然回到 你的掌控之中
Why did it freeze and then suddenly come back to life like that?
为什么会出现程序停滞又突然 回复正常的情况?
More often than not, your app is trying to process something that takes a long
多半是因为你的应用正在尝试 处理某些耗时的
time, such as grabbing some information from the Internet.
工作 例如从 Internet 中 获取信息
The issue is that something like a network request
问题是 如果 Internet 连接 不稳定 或者
can take a really long time if the Internet connection is flaky, or
需要传输大量数据 网络请求等工作
if there's a lot of data to transfer.
则可能就会花费很长的时间
We need to set up the connection with the web server, send the request,
我们必须设置与 web 服务器 的连接、发送请求、
wait for a response, and then parse the response.
等待响应 然后解析该响应
Nothing else can happen on the main thread when you're waiting for
在你等待整个过程 完成时 主线程中
this entire round trip to finish.
不会发生任何事情
So, if the user clicks other buttons in the app while the network
所以 如果用户在网络请求 发生时点击应用中的
request is happening,
其他按钮
the app can't respond to the user until it's finished that network operation.
在完成网络操作之前 该应用 无法对用户作出响应
Even worse, if the user angrily taps the button several more times,
更糟糕的是 如果用户愤怒地 多次点击按钮
those events will just get cued up until that app has completed the current task.
则会对这些事件进行提示 直到 应用完成当前的任务
If you ask the UI thread to process something that could take some time, you
如果你在应用被使用的情况下 请求 UI 线程处理
run the risk of having your app appear to freeze up when it's being used.
耗时的工作 则将会面临应用 停滞的风险
Actually, if your app blocks the UI thread for
事实上 如果你的应用 阻塞 UI 线程
more than a few seconds, Androids can display a dialog telling you,
超过一定时间 Androids 将会显示对话框告知
the user, that your app is unresponsive, and ask if the user wants to close it.
用户 你的应用未响应 并询问用户是否要将其关闭
This brings us to an important rule when building apps in Android.
这为我们在 Android 中构建应用 提供了一条重要规则
Do not block the main UI thread.
即不要阻塞主 UI 线程
Luckily, Android devices are great a multitasking.
幸运的是 Android 设备 擅长多任务处理
&gt;&gt; Yeah? &gt;&gt; Yeah.
— 是吗? — 是的
&gt;&gt; If the user clicks a button, we want the app to responsive to user input.
— 如果用户点击按钮 我们希望 应用响应用户的输入
The solution to this problem is to have the network request,
此问题的解决方法就是 在各个独立的后台线程
the number crunching, and the audio playback all processing on separate
或工作者线程中处理 网络请求、数据处理
background threads, or worker threads, thereby freeing up the UI so
和音频播放等工作 从而释放 UI 以便
that the user can still scroll and tap, and do whatever else they need to do
用户在等待所有作业 完成的过程中仍可以
with your app while they're waiting for all these other jobs to finish.
使用应用进行滚动和点击并 进行任何操作
&gt;&gt; So in theory, you could use as many threads as you need, right?
— 所以理论上 你想用多少线程 就可以用多少 对吧?
That means more work to be executed in parallel.
就是说可以并行执行 更多的工作
&gt;&gt; Yes.
— 是的
But for this app, we only need a single background thread.
但这个应用 只需要一个后台线程
The background thread can only do one operation at a time, but
后台线程一次只能 进行一项操作 但是
if the network request is going to take a really long time because
如果因为 Internet 连接很慢 或不稳定导致
you're on a slow Internet connection, or it's flaky, then that's okay.
网络请求需要花费较长时间 那也没关系
The main thread can still handle all the user-input events quickly without
主线程仍然可以在不影响 用户体验的情况下
any impact on the user experience.
快速处理所有用户输入事件
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and one more thing.
— 没错 另外
After the background work is done,
后台工作完成之后
then there's no need to keep that thread active.
就没有必要让该线程 继续处于活动状态
So, in this video, we've learned that your app can split jobs
在本视频中 我们了解到 应用可以将作业拆分
into separate threads to allow certain tasks to be processed in the background
到单个线程中 从而可以在 后台处理特定任务
while keeping the UI thread clear,
同时让 UI 线程保持空闲状态
which means that you can make the app more usable and faster.
这意味着可以让应用 更加快速可用